- id: k-joyo-60aa
  prompt: "Meanings: bad, vice, rascal\nOnyomi: アク, オ\nKunyomi: わる.い, わる-, あ.し, にく.い"
  answers:
    - 悪
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-5b89
  prompt: "Meanings: relax, cheap, low\nOnyomi: アン\nKunyomi: やす.い, やす.まる, やす, やす.らか"
  answers:
    - 安
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-6697
  prompt: "Meanings: darkness, disappear, shade\nOnyomi: アン\nKunyomi: くら.い, くら.む, くれ.る"
  answers:
    - 暗
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-533b
  prompt: "Meanings: doctor, medicine\nOnyomi: イ\nKunyomi: い.やす, い.する, くすし"
  answers:
    - 医
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-59d4
  prompt: "Meanings: committee, entrust to, leave to\nOnyomi: イ\nKunyomi: ゆだ.ねる"
  answers:
    - 委
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-610f
  prompt: "Meanings: idea, mind, heart\nOnyomi: イ"
  answers:
    - 意
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-80b2
  prompt: "Meanings: bring up, grow up, raise\nOnyomi: イク\nKunyomi: そだ.つ, そだ.ち, そだ.てる, はぐく.む"
  answers:
    - 育
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-54e1
  prompt: "Meanings: employee, member, number\nOnyomi: イン"
  answers:
    - 員
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-9662
  prompt: "Meanings: Inst., institution, temple\nOnyomi: イン"
  answers:
    - 院
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-98f2
  prompt: "Meanings: drink, smoke, take\nOnyomi: イン, オン\nKunyomi: の.む, -の.み"
  answers:
    - 飲
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-904b
  prompt: "Meanings: carry, luck, destiny\nOnyomi: ウン\nKunyomi: はこ.ぶ"
  answers:
    - 運
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-6cf3
  prompt: "Meanings: swim\nOnyomi: エイ\nKunyomi: およ.ぐ"
  answers:
    - 泳
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-99c5
  prompt: "Meanings: station\nOnyomi: エキ"
  answers:
    - 駅
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-592e
  prompt: "Meanings: center, middle\nOnyomi: オウ"
  answers:
    - 央
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-6a2a
  prompt: "Meanings: sideways, side, horizontal\nOnyomi: オウ\nKunyomi: よこ"
  answers:
    - 横
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-5c4b
  prompt: "Meanings: roof, house, shop\nOnyomi: オク\nKunyomi: や"
  answers:
    - 屋
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-6e29
  prompt: "Meanings: warm\nOnyomi: オン\nKunyomi: あたた.か, あたた.かい, あたた.まる, あたた.める"
  answers:
    - 温
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-5316
  prompt: "Meanings: change, take the form of, influence\nOnyomi: カ, ケ\nKunyomi: ば.ける, ば.かす, ふ.ける, け.する"
  answers:
    - 化
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-8377
  prompt: "Meanings: baggage, shoulder-pole load, bear (a burden)\nOnyomi: カ\nKunyomi: に"
  answers:
    - 荷
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-754c
  prompt: "Meanings: world, boundary\nOnyomi: カイ"
  answers:
    - 界
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-958b
  prompt: "Meanings: open, unfold, unseal\nOnyomi: カイ\nKunyomi: ひら.く, ひら.き, -びら.き, ひら.ける"
  answers:
    - 開
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-968e
  prompt: "Meanings: storey, stair, counter for storeys of a building\nOnyomi: カイ\nKunyomi: きざはし"
  answers:
    - 階
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-5bd2
  prompt: "Meanings: cold\nOnyomi: カン\nKunyomi: さむ.い"
  answers:
    - 寒
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-611f
  prompt: "Meanings: emotion, feeling, sensation\nOnyomi: カン"
  answers:
    - 感
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-6f22
  prompt: "Meanings: Sino-, China\nOnyomi: カン"
  answers:
    - 漢
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-9928
  prompt: "Meanings: building, mansion, large building\nOnyomi: カン\nKunyomi: やかた, たて"
  answers:
    - 館
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-5cb8
  prompt: "Meanings: beach\nOnyomi: ガン\nKunyomi: きし"
  answers:
    - 岸
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-8d77
  prompt: "Meanings: rouse, wake up, get up\nOnyomi: キ\nKunyomi: お.きる, お.こる, お.こす, おこ.す"
  answers:
    - 起
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-671f
  prompt: "Meanings: period, time, date\nOnyomi: キ, ゴ"
  answers:
    - 期
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-5ba2
  prompt: "Meanings: guest, visitor, customer\nOnyomi: キャク, カク"
  answers:
    - 客
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-7a76
  prompt: "Meanings: research, study\nOnyomi: キュウ, ク\nKunyomi: きわ.める"
  answers:
    - 究
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-6025
  prompt: "Meanings: hurry, emergency, sudden\nOnyomi: キュウ\nKunyomi: いそ.ぐ, いそ.ぎ, せ.く"
  answers:
    - 急
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-7d1a
  prompt: "Meanings: class, rank, grade\nOnyomi: キュウ"
  answers:
    - 級
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-5bae
  prompt: "Meanings: Shinto shrine, constellations, palace\nOnyomi: キュウ, グウ, ク, クウ\nKunyomi: みや"
  answers:
    - 宮
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-7403
  prompt: "Meanings: ball, sphere\nOnyomi: キュウ\nKunyomi: たま"
  answers:
    - 球
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-53bb
  prompt: "Meanings: gone, past, quit\nOnyomi: キョ, コ\nKunyomi: さ.る, -さ.る"
  answers:
    - 去
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-6a4b
  prompt: "Meanings: bridge\nOnyomi: キョウ\nKunyomi: はし"
  answers:
    - 橋
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-696d
  prompt: "Meanings: business, vocation, arts\nOnyomi: ギョウ, ゴウ\nKunyomi: わざ"
  answers:
    - 業
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-66f2
  prompt: "Meanings: bend, music, melody\nOnyomi: キョク\nKunyomi: ま.がる, ま.げる, くま"
  answers:
    - 曲
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-5c40
  prompt: "Meanings: bureau, board, office\nOnyomi: キョク\nKunyomi: つぼね"
  answers:
    - 局
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-9280
  prompt: "Meanings: silver\nOnyomi: ギン\nKunyomi: しろがね"
  answers:
    - 銀
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-533a
  prompt: "Meanings: ward, district\nOnyomi: ク, オウ, コウ"
  answers:
    - 区
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-82e6
  prompt: "Meanings: suffering, trial, worry\nOnyomi: ク\nKunyomi: くる.しい, -ぐる.しい, くる.しむ, くる.しめる"
  answers:
    - 苦
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-5177
  prompt: "Meanings: tool, utensil, means\nOnyomi: グ\nKunyomi: そな.える, つぶさ.に"
  answers:
    - 具
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-541b
  prompt: "Meanings: mister, you, ruler\nOnyomi: クン\nKunyomi: きみ, -ぎみ"
  answers:
    - 君
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-4fc2
  prompt: "Meanings: person in charge, connection, duty\nOnyomi: ケイ\nKunyomi: かか.る, かかり, -がかり, かか.わる"
  answers:
    - 係
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-8efd
  prompt: "Meanings: lightly, trifling, unimportant\nOnyomi: ケイ, キョウ, キン\nKunyomi: かる.い, かろ.やか, かろ.んじる"
  answers:
    - 軽
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-8840
  prompt: "Meanings: blood\nOnyomi: ケツ\nKunyomi: ち"
  answers:
    - 血
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-6c7a
  prompt: "Meanings: decide, fix, agree upon\nOnyomi: ケツ\nKunyomi: き.める, -ぎ.め, き.まる, さ.く"
  answers:
    - 決
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-7814
  prompt: "Meanings: polish, study of, sharpen\nOnyomi: ケン\nKunyomi: と.ぐ"
  answers:
    - 研
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-770c
  prompt: "Meanings: prefecture\nOnyomi: ケン\nKunyomi: か.ける"
  answers:
    - 県
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-5eab
  prompt: "Meanings: warehouse, storehouse\nOnyomi: コ, ク\nKunyomi: くら"
  answers:
    - 庫
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-6e56
  prompt: "Meanings: lake\nOnyomi: コ\nKunyomi: みずうみ"
  answers:
    - 湖
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-5411
  prompt: "Meanings: yonder, facing, beyond\nOnyomi: コウ\nKunyomi: む.く, む.い, -む.き, む.ける"
  answers:
    - 向
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-5e78
  prompt: "Meanings: happiness, blessing, fortune\nOnyomi: コウ\nKunyomi: さいわ.い, さち, しあわ.せ"
  answers:
    - 幸
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-6e2f
  prompt: "Meanings: harbor\nOnyomi: コウ\nKunyomi: みなと"
  answers:
    - 港
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-53f7
  prompt: "Meanings: nickname, number, item\nOnyomi: ゴウ\nKunyomi: さけ.ぶ, よびな"
  answers:
    - 号
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-6839
  prompt: "Meanings: root, radical, head (pimple)\nOnyomi: コン\nKunyomi: ね, -ね"
  answers:
    - 根
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-796d
  prompt: "Meanings: ritual, offer prayers, celebrate\nOnyomi: サイ\nKunyomi: まつ.る, まつ.り, まつり"
  answers:
    - 祭
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-76bf
  prompt: "Meanings: dish, a helping, plate\nOnyomi: ベイ\nKunyomi: さら"
  answers:
    - 皿
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-4ed5
  prompt: "Meanings: attend, doing, official\nOnyomi: シ, ジ\nKunyomi: つか.える"
  answers:
    - 仕
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-6b7b
  prompt: "Meanings: death, die\nOnyomi: シ\nKunyomi: し.ぬ, し.に-"
  answers:
    - 死
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-4f7f
  prompt: "Meanings: use, send on a mission, order\nOnyomi: シ\nKunyomi: つか.う, つか.い, -つか.い, -づか.い"
  answers:
    - 使
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-59cb
  prompt: "Meanings: commence, begin\nOnyomi: シ\nKunyomi: はじ.める, -はじ.める, はじ.まる"
  answers:
    - 始
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-6307
  prompt: "Meanings: finger, point to, indicate\nOnyomi: シ\nKunyomi: ゆび, さ.す, -さ.し"
  answers:
    - 指
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-6b6f
  prompt: "Meanings: tooth, cog\nOnyomi: シ\nKunyomi: よわい, は, よわ.い, よわい.する"
  answers:
    - 歯
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-8a69
  prompt: "Meanings: poem, poetry\nOnyomi: シ\nKunyomi: うた"
  answers:
    - 詩
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-6b21
  prompt: "Meanings: next, order, sequence\nOnyomi: ジ, シ\nKunyomi: つ.ぐ, つぎ"
  answers:
    - 次
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-4e8b
  prompt: "Meanings: matter, thing, fact\nOnyomi: ジ, ズ\nKunyomi: こと, つか.う, つか.える"
  answers:
    - 事
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-6301
  prompt: "Meanings: hold, have\nOnyomi: ジ\nKunyomi: も.つ, -も.ち, も.てる"
  answers:
    - 持
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-5f0f
  prompt: "Meanings: style, ceremony, rite\nOnyomi: シキ"
  answers:
    - 式
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-5b9f
  prompt: "Meanings: reality, truth, seed\nOnyomi: ジツ, シツ\nKunyomi: み, みの.る, まこと, みの"
  answers:
    - 実
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-5199
  prompt: "Meanings: copy, be photographed, describe\nOnyomi: シャ, ジャ\nKunyomi: うつ.す, うつ.る, うつ-, うつ.し"
  answers:
    - 写
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-8005
  prompt: "Meanings: someone, person\nOnyomi: シャ\nKunyomi: もの"
  answers:
    - 者
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-4e3b
  prompt: "Meanings: lord, chief, master\nOnyomi: シュ, ス, シュウ\nKunyomi: ぬし, おも, あるじ"
  answers:
    - 主
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-5b88
  prompt: "Meanings: guard, protect, defend\nOnyomi: シュ, ス\nKunyomi: まも.る, まも.り, もり, -もり"
  answers:
    - 守
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-53d6
  prompt: "Meanings: take, fetch, take up\nOnyomi: シュ\nKunyomi: と.る, と.り, と.り-, とり"
  answers:
    - 取
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-9152
  prompt: "Meanings: sake, alcohol\nOnyomi: シュ\nKunyomi: さけ, さか-"
  answers:
    - 酒
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-53d7
  prompt: "Meanings: accept, undergo, answer (phone)\nOnyomi: ジュ\nKunyomi: う.ける, -う.け, う.かる"
  answers:
    - 受
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-5dde
  prompt: "Meanings: state, province\nOnyomi: シュウ, ス\nKunyomi: す"
  answers:
    - 州
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-62fe
  prompt: "Meanings: pick up, gather, find\nOnyomi: シュウ, ジュウ\nKunyomi: ひろ.う"
  answers:
    - 拾
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-7d42
  prompt: "Meanings: end, finish\nOnyomi: シュウ\nKunyomi: お.わる, -お.わる, おわ.る, お.える"
  answers:
    - 終
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-7fd2
  prompt: "Meanings: learn\nOnyomi: シュウ, ジュ\nKunyomi: なら.う, なら.い"
  answers:
    - 習
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-96c6
  prompt: "Meanings: gather, meet, congregate\nOnyomi: シュウ\nKunyomi: あつ.まる, あつ.める, つど.う"
  answers:
    - 集
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-4f4f
  prompt: "Meanings: dwell, reside, live\nOnyomi: ジュウ, ヂュウ, チュウ\nKunyomi: す.む, す.まう, -ず.まい"
  answers:
    - 住
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-91cd
  prompt: "Meanings: heavy, important, esteem\nOnyomi: ジュウ, チョウ\nKunyomi: え, おも.い, おも.り, おも.なう"
  answers:
    - 重
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-5bbf
  prompt: "Meanings: inn, lodging, relay station\nOnyomi: シュク\nKunyomi: やど, やど.る, やど.す"
  answers:
    - 宿
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-6240
  prompt: "Meanings: place, extent\nOnyomi: ショ\nKunyomi: ところ, -ところ, どころ, とこ"
  answers:
    - 所
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-6691
  prompt: "Meanings: sultry, hot, summer heat\nOnyomi: ショ\nKunyomi: あつ.い"
  answers:
    - 暑
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-52a9
  prompt: "Meanings: help, rescue, assist\nOnyomi: ジョ\nKunyomi: たす.ける, たす.かる, す.ける, すけ"
  answers:
    - 助
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-662d
  prompt: "Meanings: shining, bright\nOnyomi: ショウ"
  answers:
    - 昭
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-6d88
  prompt: "Meanings: extinguish, blow out, turn off\nOnyomi: ショウ\nKunyomi: き.える, け.す"
  answers:
    - 消
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-5546
  prompt: "Meanings: make a deal, selling, dealing in\nOnyomi: ショウ\nKunyomi: あきな.う"
  answers:
    - 商
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-7ae0
  prompt: "Meanings: badge, chapter, composition\nOnyomi: ショウ"
  answers:
    - 章
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-52dd
  prompt: "Meanings: victory, win, prevail\nOnyomi: ショウ\nKunyomi: か.つ, -が.ち, まさ.る, すぐ.れる"
  answers:
    - 勝
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-4e57
  prompt: "Meanings: ride, power, multiplication\nOnyomi: ジョウ, ショウ\nKunyomi: の.る, -の.り, の.せる"
  answers:
    - 乗
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-690d
  prompt: "Meanings: plant\nOnyomi: ショク\nKunyomi: う.える, う.わる"
  answers:
    - 植
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-7533
  prompt: "Meanings: have the honor to, sign of the monkey, 3-5PM\nOnyomi: シン\nKunyomi: もう.す, もう.し-, さる"
  answers:
    - 申
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-8eab
  prompt: "Meanings: somebody, person, one's station in life\nOnyomi: シン\nKunyomi: み"
  answers:
    - 身
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-795e
  prompt: "Meanings: gods, mind, soul\nOnyomi: シン, ジン\nKunyomi: かみ, かん-, こう-"
  answers:
    - 神
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-771f
  prompt: "Meanings: true, reality, Buddhist sect\nOnyomi: シン\nKunyomi: ま, ま-, まこと"
  answers:
    - 真
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-6df1
  prompt: "Meanings: deep, heighten, intensify\nOnyomi: シン\nKunyomi: ふか.い, -ぶか.い, ふか.まる, ふか.める"
  answers:
    - 深
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-9032
  prompt: "Meanings: advance, proceed, progress\nOnyomi: シン\nKunyomi: すす.む, すす.める"
  answers:
    - 進
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-4e16
  prompt: "Meanings: generation, world, society\nOnyomi: セイ, セ, ソウ\nKunyomi: よ"
  answers:
    - 世
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-6574
  prompt: "Meanings: organize, arranging, tune\nOnyomi: セイ\nKunyomi: ととの.える, ととの.う"
  answers:
    - 整
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-6614
  prompt: "Meanings: once upon a time, antiquity, old times\nOnyomi: セキ, シャク\nKunyomi: むかし"
  answers:
    - 昔
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-5168
  prompt: "Meanings: whole, entire, all\nOnyomi: ゼン\nKunyomi: まった.く, すべ.て"
  answers:
    - 全
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-76f8
  prompt: "Meanings: inter-, mutual, together\nOnyomi: ソウ, ショウ\nKunyomi: あい-"
  answers:
    - 相
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-9001
  prompt: "Meanings: escort, send\nOnyomi: ソウ\nKunyomi: おく.る"
  answers:
    - 送
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-60f3
  prompt: "Meanings: idea, thought, conception\nOnyomi: ソウ, ソ\nKunyomi: おも.う"
  answers:
    - 想
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-606f
  prompt: "Meanings: breath, respiration, son\nOnyomi: ソク\nKunyomi: いき"
  answers:
    - 息
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-901f
  prompt: "Meanings: quick, fast\nOnyomi: ソク\nKunyomi: はや.い, はや-, はや.める, すみ.やか"
  answers:
    - 速
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-65cf
  prompt: "Meanings: tribe, family\nOnyomi: ゾク"
  answers:
    - 族
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-4ed6
  prompt: "Meanings: other, another, the others\nOnyomi: タ\nKunyomi: ほか"
  answers:
    - 他
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-6253
  prompt: "Meanings: strike, hit, knock\nOnyomi: ダ, ダース\nKunyomi: う.つ, う.ち-, ぶ.つ"
  answers:
    - 打
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-5bfe
  prompt: "Meanings: vis-a-vis, opposite, even\nOnyomi: タイ, ツイ\nKunyomi: あいて, こた.える, そろ.い, つれあ.い"
  answers:
    - 対
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-5f85
  prompt: "Meanings: wait, depend on\nOnyomi: タイ\nKunyomi: ま.つ, -ま.ち"
  answers:
    - 待
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-4ee3
  prompt: "Meanings: substitute, change, convert\nOnyomi: ダイ, タイ\nKunyomi: か.わる, かわ.る, かわ.り, か.わり"
  answers:
    - 代
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-7b2c
  prompt: "Meanings: No., residence\nOnyomi: ダイ, テイ"
  answers:
    - 第
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-984c
  prompt: "Meanings: topic, subject\nOnyomi: ダイ"
  answers:
    - 題
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-70ad
  prompt: "Meanings: charcoal, coal\nOnyomi: タン\nKunyomi: すみ"
  answers:
    - 炭
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-77ed
  prompt: "Meanings: short, brevity, fault\nOnyomi: タン\nKunyomi: みじか.い"
  answers:
    - 短
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-8ac7
  prompt: "Meanings: discuss, talk\nOnyomi: ダン"
  answers:
    - 談
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-7740
  prompt: "Meanings: don, arrive, wear\nOnyomi: チャク, ジャク\nKunyomi: き.る, き.せる, つ.く, つ.ける"
  answers:
    - 着
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-6ce8
  prompt: "Meanings: pour, irrigate, shed (tears)\nOnyomi: チュウ\nKunyomi: そそ.ぐ, さ.す, つ.ぐ"
  answers:
    - 注
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-67f1
  prompt: "Meanings: pillar, post, cylinder\nOnyomi: チュウ\nKunyomi: はしら"
  answers:
    - 柱
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-4e01
  prompt: "Meanings: street, ward, town\nOnyomi: チョウ, テイ, チン, トウ\nKunyomi: ひのと"
  answers:
    - 丁
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-5e33
  prompt: "Meanings: notebook, account book, album\nOnyomi: チョウ\nKunyomi: とばり"
  answers:
    - 帳
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-8abf
  prompt: "Meanings: tune, tone, meter\nOnyomi: チョウ\nKunyomi: しら.べる, しら.べ, ととの.う, ととの.える"
  answers:
    - 調
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-8ffd
  prompt: "Meanings: chase, drive away, follow\nOnyomi: ツイ\nKunyomi: お.う"
  answers:
    - 追
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-5b9a
  prompt: "Meanings: determine, fix, establish\nOnyomi: テイ, ジョウ\nKunyomi: さだ.める, さだ.まる, さだ.か"
  answers:
    - 定
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-5ead
  prompt: "Meanings: courtyard, garden, yard\nOnyomi: テイ\nKunyomi: にわ"
  answers:
    - 庭
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-7b1b
  prompt: "Meanings: flute, clarinet, pipe\nOnyomi: テキ\nKunyomi: ふえ"
  answers:
    - 笛
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-9244
  prompt: "Meanings: iron\nOnyomi: テツ\nKunyomi: くろがね"
  answers:
    - 鉄
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-8ee2
  prompt: "Meanings: revolve, turn around, change\nOnyomi: テン\nKunyomi: ころ.がる, ころ.げる, ころ.がす, ころ.ぶ"
  answers:
    - 転
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-90fd
  prompt: "Meanings: metropolis, capital, all\nOnyomi: ト, ツ\nKunyomi: みやこ"
  answers:
    - 都
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-5ea6
  prompt: "Meanings: degrees, occurrence, time\nOnyomi: ド, ト, タク\nKunyomi: たび, -た.い"
  answers:
    - 度
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-6295
  prompt: "Meanings: throw, discard, abandon\nOnyomi: トウ\nKunyomi: な.げる, -な.げ"
  answers:
    - 投
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-8c46
  prompt: "Meanings: beans, pea, midget\nOnyomi: トウ, ズ\nKunyomi: まめ, まめ-"
  answers:
    - 豆
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-5cf6
  prompt: "Meanings: island\nOnyomi: トウ\nKunyomi: しま"
  answers:
    - 島
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-6e6f
  prompt: "Meanings: hot water, bath, hot spring\nOnyomi: トウ\nKunyomi: ゆ"
  answers:
    - 湯
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-767b
  prompt: "Meanings: ascend, climb up\nOnyomi: トウ, ト, ドウ, ショウ\nKunyomi: のぼ.る, あ.がる"
  answers:
    - 登
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-7b49
  prompt: "Meanings: etc., and so forth, class (first)\nOnyomi: トウ\nKunyomi: ひと.しい, など, -ら"
  answers:
    - 等
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-52d5
  prompt: "Meanings: move, motion, change\nOnyomi: ドウ\nKunyomi: うご.く, うご.かす"
  answers:
    - 動
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-7ae5
  prompt: "Meanings: juvenile, child\nOnyomi: ドウ\nKunyomi: わらべ"
  answers:
    - 童
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-8fb2
  prompt: "Meanings: agriculture, farmers\nOnyomi: ノウ"
  answers:
    - 農
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-6ce2
  prompt: "Meanings: waves, billows, Poland\nOnyomi: ハ\nKunyomi: なみ"
  answers:
    - 波
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-914d
  prompt: "Meanings: distribute, spouse, exile\nOnyomi: ハイ\nKunyomi: くば.る"
  answers:
    - 配
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-500d
  prompt: "Meanings: double, twice, times\nOnyomi: バイ"
  answers:
    - 倍
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-7bb1
  prompt: "Meanings: box, chest, case\nOnyomi: ソウ\nKunyomi: はこ"
  answers:
    - 箱
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-7551
  prompt: "Meanings: farm, field, garden\nKunyomi: はた, はたけ, -ばたけ"
  answers:
    - 畑
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-767a
  prompt: "Meanings: departure, discharge, publish\nOnyomi: ハツ, ホツ\nKunyomi: た.つ, あば.く, おこ.る, つか.わす"
  answers:
    - 発
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-53cd
  prompt: "Meanings: anti-\nOnyomi: ハン, ホン, タン, ホ\nKunyomi: そ.る, そ.らす, かえ.す, かえ.る"
  answers:
    - 反
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-5742
  prompt: "Meanings: slope, incline, hill\nOnyomi: ハン\nKunyomi: さか"
  answers:
    - 坂
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-677f
  prompt: "Meanings: plank, board, plate\nOnyomi: ハン, バン\nKunyomi: いた"
  answers:
    - 板
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-76ae
  prompt: "Meanings: pelt, skin, hide\nOnyomi: ヒ\nKunyomi: かわ"
  answers:
    - 皮
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-60b2
  prompt: "Meanings: grieve, sad, deplore\nOnyomi: ヒ\nKunyomi: かな.しい, かな.しむ"
  answers:
    - 悲
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-7f8e
  prompt: "Meanings: beauty, beautiful\nOnyomi: ビ, ミ\nKunyomi: うつく.しい"
  answers:
    - 美
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-9f3b
  prompt: "Meanings: nose, snout\nOnyomi: ビ\nKunyomi: はな"
  answers:
    - 鼻
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-7b46
  prompt: "Meanings: writing brush, writing, painting brush\nOnyomi: ヒツ\nKunyomi: ふで"
  answers:
    - 筆
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-6c37
  prompt: "Meanings: icicle, ice, hail\nOnyomi: ヒョウ\nKunyomi: こおり, ひ, こお.る"
  answers:
    - 氷
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-8868
  prompt: "Meanings: surface, table, chart\nOnyomi: ヒョウ\nKunyomi: おもて, -おもて, あらわ.す, あらわ.れる"
  answers:
    - 表
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-79d2
  prompt: "Meanings: second (1/60 minute)\nOnyomi: ビョウ"
  answers:
    - 秒
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-75c5
  prompt: "Meanings: ill, sick\nOnyomi: ビョウ, ヘイ\nKunyomi: や.む, -や.み, やまい"
  answers:
    - 病
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-54c1
  prompt: "Meanings: goods, refinement, dignity\nOnyomi: ヒン, ホン\nKunyomi: しな"
  answers:
    - 品
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-8ca0
  prompt: "Meanings: defeat, negative, -\nOnyomi: フ\nKunyomi: ま.ける, ま.かす, お.う"
  answers:
    - 負
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-90e8
  prompt: "Meanings: section, bureau, dept\nOnyomi: ブ\nKunyomi: -べ"
  answers:
    - 部
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-670d
  prompt: "Meanings: clothing, admit, obey\nOnyomi: フク"
  answers:
    - 服
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-798f
  prompt: "Meanings: blessing, fortune, luck\nOnyomi: フク"
  answers:
    - 福
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-7269
  prompt: "Meanings: thing, object, matter\nOnyomi: ブツ, モツ\nKunyomi: もの, もの-"
  answers:
    - 物
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-5e73
  prompt: "Meanings: even, flat, peace\nOnyomi: ヘイ, ビョウ, ヒョウ\nKunyomi: たい.ら, たい.らげる, ひら"
  answers:
    - 平
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-8fd4
  prompt: "Meanings: return, answer, fade\nOnyomi: ヘン\nKunyomi: かえ.す, -かえ.す, かえ.る, -かえ.る"
  answers:
    - 返
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-52c9
  prompt: "Meanings: exertion, endeavour, encourage\nOnyomi: ベン\nKunyomi: つと.める"
  answers:
    - 勉
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-653e
  prompt: "Meanings: set free, release, fire\nOnyomi: ホウ\nKunyomi: はな.す, -っぱな.し, はな.つ, はな.れる"
  answers:
    - 放
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-5473
  prompt: "Meanings: flavor, taste\nOnyomi: ミ\nKunyomi: あじ, あじ.わう"
  answers:
    - 味
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-547d
  prompt: "Meanings: fate, command, decree\nOnyomi: メイ, ミョウ\nKunyomi: いのち"
  answers:
    - 命
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-9762
  prompt: "Meanings: mask, face, features\nOnyomi: メン, ベン\nKunyomi: おも, おもて, つら"
  answers:
    - 面
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-554f
  prompt: "Meanings: question, ask, problem\nOnyomi: モン\nKunyomi: と.う, と.い, とん"
  answers:
    - 問
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-5f79
  prompt: "Meanings: duty, war, campaign\nOnyomi: ヤク, エキ"
  answers:
    - 役
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-85ac
  prompt: "Meanings: medicine, chemical, enamel\nOnyomi: ヤク\nKunyomi: くすり"
  answers:
    - 薬
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-7531
  prompt: "Meanings: wherefore, a reason\nOnyomi: ユ, ユウ, ユイ\nKunyomi: よし, よ.る"
  answers:
    - 由
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-6cb9
  prompt: "Meanings: oil, fat\nOnyomi: ユ, ユウ\nKunyomi: あぶら"
  answers:
    - 油
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-6709
  prompt: "Meanings: possess, have, exist\nOnyomi: ユウ, ウ\nKunyomi: あ.る"
  answers:
    - 有
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-904a
  prompt: "Meanings: play\nOnyomi: ユウ, ユ\nKunyomi: あそ.ぶ, あそ.ばす"
  answers:
    - 遊
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-4e88
  prompt: "Meanings: beforehand, previous, myself\nOnyomi: ヨ, シャ\nKunyomi: あらかじ.め"
  answers:
    - 予
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-7f8a
  prompt: "Meanings: sheep\nOnyomi: ヨウ\nKunyomi: ひつじ"
  answers:
    - 羊
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-6d0b
  prompt: "Meanings: ocean, sea, foreign\nOnyomi: ヨウ"
  answers:
    - 洋
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-8449
  prompt: "Meanings: leaf, plane, lobe\nOnyomi: ヨウ\nKunyomi: は"
  answers:
    - 葉
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-967d
  prompt: "Meanings: sunshine, yang principle, positive\nOnyomi: ヨウ\nKunyomi: ひ"
  answers:
    - 陽
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-69d8
  prompt: "Meanings: Esq., way, manner\nOnyomi: ヨウ, ショウ\nKunyomi: さま, さん"
  answers:
    - 様
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-843d
  prompt: "Meanings: fall, drop, come down\nOnyomi: ラク\nKunyomi: お.ちる, お.ち, お.とす"
  answers:
    - 落
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-6d41
  prompt: "Meanings: current, a sink, flow\nOnyomi: リュウ, ル\nKunyomi: なが.れる, なが.れ, なが.す, -なが.す"
  answers:
    - 流
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-65c5
  prompt: "Meanings: trip, travel\nOnyomi: リョ\nKunyomi: たび"
  answers:
    - 旅
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-4e21
  prompt: "Meanings: both, old Japanese coin, counter for carriages (e.g., in a train)\nOnyomi: リョウ\nKunyomi: てる, ふたつ"
  answers:
    - 両
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-7dd1
  prompt: "Meanings: green\nOnyomi: リョク, ロク\nKunyomi: みどり"
  answers:
    - 緑
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-793c
  prompt: "Meanings: salute, bow, ceremony\nOnyomi: レイ, ライ"
  answers:
    - 礼
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-5217
  prompt: "Meanings: file, row, rank\nOnyomi: レツ, レ"
  answers:
    - 列
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-7df4
  prompt: "Meanings: practice, gloss, train\nOnyomi: レン\nKunyomi: ね.る, ね.り"
  answers:
    - 練
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-8def
  prompt: "Meanings: path, route, road\nOnyomi: ロ, ル\nKunyomi: -じ, みち"
  answers:
    - 路
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-548c
  prompt: "Meanings: harmony, Japanese style, peace\nOnyomi: ワ, オ, カ\nKunyomi: やわ.らぐ, やわ.らげる, なご.む, なご.やか"
  answers:
    - 和
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  invulnerable: false
  max_stage: -1
  learned: false
  hidden: false
  befuddlers: []
